# Joseph Ford

Full-Stack Developer

New Zealand (Resident Visa) | josephwford@outlook.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

## **Profile**

With a background in social science and a grounding in full-stack web development technologies, I bring critical thinking, strong communication, and attention to detail to all that I do. Having worked on a range of projects, I want to continue using my skills to find innovative solutions to complex problems.

# **Experience**

Full-Stack Developer (student)

Dev Academy, New Zealand | January 2023 - April 2023

This was an intensive web development bootcamp. During the course, I became proficient in a range of technologies. These included core web development technologies (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript/TypeScript), as well as React (including state management with Redux), Node, Express, and SQLite.

Employing these technologies while working alongside others also gave me the opportunity to cultivate non-technical skills such as teamworking, communication, and stress management. For the final project week, I worked on a subscription-tracking application (SubMinder), focusing largely on the back-end routing and API for adding, updating, and removing subscriptions.

#### Career break

New Zealand | May 2022 – January 2023

I took this career break to help care for a family member. I also spent this time peer reviewing for journals, picking up new technical skills, and, in the later stages, preparing to start Dev Academy.

### Conversation Analyst (full-time)

University of Sheffield, United Kingdom | Feb 2021 – March 2022, May 2022
This was a project studying the shift to telemedicine in seizure clinics during the
Covid-19 pandemic. I was a co-applicant on the funding application and, once the
project had started, was responsible for day-to-day management. Specific

responsibilities included managing and collecting data, analysing data using qualitative and quantitative methods, and writing publications. I also designed and conducted a systematic review and narrative synthesis.

Data Technician and Training Module Developer (casual)

Loughborough University, United Kingdom | Oct 2019 – Feb 2021

This was a project studying communication between doctors and patients in palliative care. In this role, my responsibilities included anonymising a large set of palliative care video data, improving data quality by synchronising videos with higher quality audio, and developing a communication skills training module for practitioners based on findings from my PhD research.

Postdoctoral Research Associate (full-time)

University of Exeter, United Kingdom | Feb 2017 – April 2019

This was a project studying mental health in low-income communities. My main role was to study how doctors and patients communicate about mental health issues. Specific responsibilities included managing and analysing a dataset comprising video data; writing publications and presenting my work at conferences; and planning and facilitating sessions at workshops, advisory board meetings, and a conference organised as part of the project.

# **Education**

Level 6 Certificate in Applied Software Development (pending)

Dev Academy Aotearoa, New Zealand | 2023

PhD in Social Sciences

Loughborough University, United Kingdom | 2017

 Awarded School of Social, Political and Geographical Sciences PhD studentship (2014)

BsC in Social Psychology (First)

Loughborough University, United Kingdom | 2012